<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="/filmRater/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/filmRater/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-07-29T22:27:21+03:00</updated><id>/filmRater/feed.xml</id><title type="html">FilmRater</title><subtitle>A website about film reviews and blog posts about films</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Reminder: UltraViolet shuts down July 31st, so safeguard your digital movies now</title><link href="/filmRater/2019/07/29/ultraviolet-digital-video-locker-shutdown-july-31-warning.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reminder: UltraViolet shuts down July 31st, so safeguard your digital movies now" /><published>2019-07-29T10:09:21+03:00</published><updated>2019-07-29T10:09:21+03:00</updated><id>/filmRater/2019/07/29/ultraviolet-digital-video-locker-shutdown-july-31-warning</id><content type="html" xml:base="/filmRater/2019/07/29/ultraviolet-digital-video-locker-shutdown-july-31-warning.html">&lt;p&gt;UltraViolet, Hollywood’s original attempt at a cross-platform digital movie locker service, is shutting down this week on July 31st. If you’ve redeemed your fair share of codes that came with Blu-rays or DVDs through the years, you’ll definitely want to make sure you’ve linked your UltraViolet collection to another retailer so you can continue accessing and streaming those titles after the service goes offline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walmart-backed Vudu is the best bet for people in the United States. I don’t foresee it shutting down anytime soon, and it supports Movies Anywhere, so you’ll be able to watch your UltraViolet collection across popular streaming devices and apps like Amazon Video or Apple TV. But you can also go with FandangoNow or Kaleidescape; the latter is only really useful to people with a fancy theater room somewhere in their house. Here’s how to make sure everything is linked correctly:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a chance that some movies or TV shows might vanish from your collection once UltraViolet goes dark. Such is the risk of never truly owning your digital content, and a shutdown FAQ acknowledges this possibility. But I don’t think it’ll be something most of us have to deal with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also don’t know what sort of person would have a large UltraViolet catalog without having ever linked it to Vudu or another service by now. But time is running out if that’s somehow the predicament you’re in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One last piece of advice: don’t manually unlink or close your UltraViolet account prior to the 31st, as “UltraViolet and retailers will be working together to maximize your continued access to movies and TV shows,” and doing so might throw a wrench into that process.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Robert Wilson</name></author><summary type="html">UltraViolet, Hollywood’s original attempt at a cross-platform digital movie locker service, is shutting down this week on July 31st. If you’ve redeemed your fair share of codes that came with Blu-rays or DVDs through the years, you’ll definitely want to make sure you’ve linked your UltraViolet collection to another retailer so you can continue accessing and streaming those titles after the service goes offline.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Avengers: Endgame finally passes Avatar as the biggest movie of all time</title><link href="/filmRater/2019/07/28/avengers-endgame-avatar-biggest-movie-box-office.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Avengers: Endgame finally passes Avatar as the biggest movie of all time" /><published>2019-07-28T19:09:21+03:00</published><updated>2019-07-28T19:09:21+03:00</updated><id>/filmRater/2019/07/28/avengers-endgame-avatar-biggest-movie-box-office</id><content type="html" xml:base="/filmRater/2019/07/28/avengers-endgame-avatar-biggest-movie-box-office.html">&lt;p&gt;Just over a month ago, Avengers: Endgame fans conceded defeat to James Cameron’s 2009 Avatar, acknowledging it would remain the biggest movie of all time. Last night at San Diego Comic-Con, Marvel Studios president Kevin Feige announced that’s no longer true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Endgame, the culmination of a 22-movie arc started by Marvel in 2008, will officially surpass Avatar as the highest grossing movie of all time either today or tomorrow. There is an approximate $500,000 difference between Endgame and Avatar, which analysts predict will close within a day. It’s why Feige could make the announcement he did at Comic-Con.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disney and Marvel Studios have been gunning for the top spot, which has been held by Cameron and 20th Century Fox (now a Disney property) for a decade. The company released a different version of Endgame in theaters on June 28th to help draw in audiences once again, promising a deleted scene (one that underwhelmed fans), a Stan Lee tribute, and an official post-credits scene. Disney and Marvel essentially sold theatergoers extras that would usually appear on the Blu-ray release, in the hope that that would be enough to drive people back into the theater one more time to put the film over the edge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the $37 million is believed to have come from offshore markets, according to Deadline, but there was a real campaign in the US to make Endgame the biggest movie of all time. (Endgame is the top movie now, but that could change due to inflation.) People on popular Marvel subreddits were organizing watch parties and encouraging their friends to go out and buy another ticket. In 2010, Den of Geek’s Simon Brew noted that fans were forced to care about box office numbers — something that up until semi-recently was largely a conversation among trades, analysts, and people who made the actual thing — because box office success translated to continuation. That’s not true with Endgame, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Marvel Cinematic Universe is already too big for Disney to suddenly worry about whether Endgame is the biggest movie of all time or the second. This isn’t a suffering independent film. Marvel’s time at Hall H last night was a reminder that, over the next three years, Disney’s superhero division is set to dominate both theatrical and streaming worlds. The message that Feige sent was simple: We own it all. Why bother competing? In many ways, it’s similar to the message Disney sent in its open and shameless attempt to surpass Avatar. It’s not success driven by shareholder concerns; Endgame already did what it was supposed to. This was success driven by ego. The brilliant move was looping in fans to make it seem like their success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Endgame became more than a singular movie because Marvel Studios, which leans on making fans feel like their part-time investors in the franchise, made it feel like more than just a franchise film to fans. Marvel Studios is about to do the same thing with Disney+, Disney’s upcoming streaming service. Fans will spend $7 a month to keep up with their favorite superheroes, and an additional $15 at the movie theater — not one, not twice, but several times. Endgame became a new stepping point for Marvel. They couldn’t just be good, they had to be the best. They couldn’t just win, they had to dominate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The Marvel fans’ desire to unseat Avatar as the top grossing film of all time is ultimately an attempt to help one of the largest corporations on this planet squeeze more money from fans and provide more value for stockholders,” Cameron Kunzelman wrote at Polygon. “It is an endeavor to strengthen a titan of entertainment that is already so swollen and dominant that some are calling for it to be broken up.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disney nor Marvel Studios are being broken up. They’re only getting bigger. And, as Feige basically pointed out at Comic-Con, it’s up to fans to help them stay that way.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Robert Wilson</name></author><summary type="html">Just over a month ago, Avengers: Endgame fans conceded defeat to James Cameron’s 2009 Avatar, acknowledging it would remain the biggest movie of all time. Last night at San Diego Comic-Con, Marvel Studios president Kevin Feige announced that’s no longer true.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Netflix’s Mindhunter will return for a second season in August</title><link href="/filmRater/2019/07/12/netflix-mindhunter-season-2-premiere-august-david-fincher-return.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Netflix’s Mindhunter will return for a second season in August" /><published>2019-07-12T12:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2019-07-12T12:00:00+03:00</updated><id>/filmRater/2019/07/12/netflix-mindhunter-season-2-premiere-august-david-fincher-return</id><content type="html" xml:base="/filmRater/2019/07/12/netflix-mindhunter-season-2-premiere-august-david-fincher-return.html">&lt;p&gt;Netflix’s Mindhunter, the David Fincher-produced crime thriller, will return for a second season on August 16th. The show follows two FBI agents from the Behavioral Science Unit — Holden Ford (Jonathan Groff) and Bill Tench (Holt McCallany) — as they travel across America to interview psychopaths and serial killers in an attempt to understand their mindset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new season, which was quickly confirmed after the show’s debut in October 2017, will focus on the Atlanta child murders of 1979–1981, which claimed at least 28 known victims. Fincher first confirmed the release date and revealed more details about the second season on KCRW’s The Treatment podcast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fincher has been increasingly involved in Netflix projects. The streaming platform announced last month that it would be ordering a second season of its adult animated series Love, Death + Robots, co-created by Fincher and Deadpool director Tim Miller. It was also reported in Variety yesterday that Fincher will be directing Netflix’s Mank, a biopic about Citizen Kane screenwriter Herman Mankiewicz, played by Gary Oldman. The movie is based on a script written by Fincher’s late father, who died in 2003. Mank will be Fincher’s first feature film since 2014’s Gone Girl, and production will begin in November.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kayla Peers</name></author><summary type="html">Netflix’s Mindhunter, the David Fincher-produced crime thriller, will return for a second season on August 16th. The show follows two FBI agents from the Behavioral Science Unit — Holden Ford (Jonathan Groff) and Bill Tench (Holt McCallany) — as they travel across America to interview psychopaths and serial killers in an attempt to understand their mindset.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Art of Self-Defense functions like a 20-year anniversary remake of Fight Club</title><link href="/filmRater/2019/07/03/art-of-self-defense-fight-club-20-year-anniversary-remake.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Art of Self-Defense functions like a 20-year anniversary remake of Fight Club" /><published>2019-07-03T16:30:00+03:00</published><updated>2019-07-03T16:30:00+03:00</updated><id>/filmRater/2019/07/03/art-of-self-defense-fight-club-20-year-anniversary-remake</id><content type="html" xml:base="/filmRater/2019/07/03/art-of-self-defense-fight-club-20-year-anniversary-remake.html">&lt;p&gt;In Riley Stearns’ new movie The Art of Self-Defense, a lonely, mild-mannered office drone has an experience that forces him to reevaluate his lowly place in a supposedly civilized society. He joins a group with a charismatic leader who encourages a reclamation of traditional masculinity built around boundary-breaking physical conflict. He meets a similarly minded woman and develops an unconventional, not-quite-romantic relationship with her. Eventually, he comes to suspect that the charismatic leader is using dangerous, extremist methods to further a megalomaniacal cause, leading to a final showdown. If this description sounds familiar without knowing anything more about this new film, you may have seen the movie Fight Club, which turns 20 this fall. At times, The Art of Self-Defense feels like an unofficial remake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stearns doesn’t explicitly position his new film as an answer to David Fincher’s cultishly beloved Chuck Palahniuk adaptation. For one thing, its gathering of desperate, lonely men is far more socially acceptable than the bare-knuckle brawling group in Fight Club. In Art of Self-Defense, the meek Casey (Jesse Eisenberg) simply joins a karate class at a local dojo, which is presided over by a quietly domineering sensei (Alessandro Nivola). Stearns also takes a more hushed, deadpan, small-scale approach to the material. He doesn’t ape Fincher’s wild stylizations, which include sardonic asides to the camera, dream-world hallucinations (like a detailed visualization of a plane crash), and heavy use of computer-animated procedural close-ups, like zooming into the guts of a stove to show the cause of an explosion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But while he eschews flashy techniques, Stearns explores similar territory. He’s studying a man who has become frustrated by the fear and anxiety that accompanied his careful attempts to abide by society’s rules. Casey, like the unnamed narrator played by Edward Norton in Fight Club, lives sequestered from physical violence. Once it enters his world — through an assault on the street, rather than Norton’s what-the-hell initial dust-up with Tyler Durden (Brad Pitt) — he wants to participate. He’s eager to finally feel like a real man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two decades since Fight Club came out have somehow made Fincher’s film look both dated and prescient. 1999 was long enough ago — before the Bush, Obama, or Trump presidencies; before 9/11; before conversations about white fragility were so frequent or pointed — that it now seems downright quaint that so many movies of that era agonized so thoroughly over the dilemmas of straight, white, well-off men. (To viewers who don’t fit those categories — and empathetic viewers who do — “quaint” may not cover it; “eye-rollingly ridiculous” might.) Movies like Falling Down, Fight Club, and American Beauty have satirical dimensions and ultimately may not endorse their characters’ most selfish or entitled views. But they do share an implicit understanding that their protagonists’ feelings of alienation are well-founded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Art of Self-Defense, Kearns clearly understands that there’s something retrograde about that concern. Maybe that’s why he set it sometime close to Fight Club’s release. Just as Fincher’s film doesn’t name its primary setting, Self-Defense doesn’t offer a particular place or period. But judging by its computers (present, but not ubiquitous, and clunky), phones (answering machines are still around), and methods of congregation (in person; no Reddit forums or app-based group chats), it’s probably happening sometime in the back half of the ’90s. It’s a half-savvy, half-suspect way of making the sensei’s regressive views on gender and masculinity more believable, even as they’re issued with a cartoonish lack of subtlety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film’s deadpan style serves this purpose, too, foregrounding its absurdity. After the initial controversy about Fight Club’s violence and irreverence faded, it gained an appreciative following and became a case study in possible misinterpretation. The movie’s big twist about Tyler Durden’s identity works as a reversal in part because it coincides with the Narrator realizing how far “Tyler” has hardened his ethos into all-out fascism. For the first half of the movie, Tyler Durden can be read as a charismatic, funny badass. He’s constantly ready with a bromide about the glories of “hitting bottom” in a fearful, consumerist society — one he views as emasculating, rather than, say, inherently misogynistic. The revelation about him sharing a body and brain space with the Narrator is unnerving because, by that point in the film, he’s also more or less the bad guy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rewatching Fight Club in 2019, that reversal feels less revelatory, not least because Brad Pitt has become a stronger, quieter actor since then, throwing the intentional shallowness of his Tyler Durden into sharper relief. (It’s also possible that 20 years of life experience would make plenty of viewers less enamored of Durden’s proto-men’s rights stylings.) But given what we now know about incels, MRAs, and the increasing popularity of open fascism, it’s still easy to see how a certain audience will always be taken in by Palahniuk’s catchphrase-y, self-aggrandizing rhetoric.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This could be why The Art of Self-Defense lacks a Tyler Durden character. Nivola’s unnamed sensei has a certain intense charisma, but the movie observes it from a remove. Though Casey is a clear figure of audience identification and his seduction into the sensei’s world of steely masculinity and brute confidence is understandable, the sensei always looks a little silly from the outside. It’s hard to imagine anyone but the most deluded audience member ever mistaking him for a genuine iconoclast in the Tyler Durden vein. The character is slightly more dignified, and certainly more credibly sinister, than, say, Danny McBride’s character in the cringe comedy The Foot Fist Way. But he’s not far off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is this the future of satirizing toxic masculinity? Making sure that as many audience members as possible will understand that a toxic male character is meant to be foolish so they don’t ever get the wrong idea? (It is possible to get some kind of wrong idea about Nivola’s character, of course — Art of Self Defense has some sharp twists and turns — but Stearns never lets him read as particularly heroic.) Debate rages on over whether it’s better to explore the incel mentality in uncomfortable depth or stop giving aggrieved men so much attention. As recently as this spring, Under the Silver Lake was criticized both for glorifying its dirtbag male protagonist and for hammering home his toxicity too hard and too early.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as similar as The Art of Self-Defense is to Fight Club in its aims and overall form, there’s no creative reason for it to do the same thing as its beloved predecessor, and it would be absurd to pretend nothing has changed in the 20 years since Fincher’s film. For that matter, Fight Club isn’t an unimpeachable work of satire. Though its narrator ultimately rejects Tyler’s reductive, destructive view of the world, his enhanced sense of empathy amounts to being less of a jerk to the one woman in his life at the last minute. The movie still springs from Tyler’s point of view, however roundabout a route it takes to get there. This makes the multiple-personality twist a rare instance of that trope being genuinely clever and thematically rich, even for those who see it coming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing in The Art of Self-Defense is so knotty, which makes it both a cleaner movie and a less interesting one. There’s less room for disastrous misinterpretation because it barely requires interpretation at all; superficially, the movie is disturbing, but its only real ambiguities are tangential mysteries over what it really thinks about gun culture. (The sensei, the movie’s scariest and most adamantly macho character, abhors them.) Stearns has made an exacting, funny, well-acted, and sometimes bruising film, but it’s also one that feels like a closed system, unlikely to warp anyone’s thinking or produce a checkered, hotly debated legacy. Fight Club’s moment may have passed, but the movie itself lingers like a scar. It may take another 20 years to figure out whether that’s better or worse.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kayla Peers</name></author><summary type="html">In Riley Stearns’ new movie The Art of Self-Defense, a lonely, mild-mannered office drone has an experience that forces him to reevaluate his lowly place in a supposedly civilized society. He joins a group with a charismatic leader who encourages a reclamation of traditional masculinity built around boundary-breaking physical conflict. He meets a similarly minded woman and develops an unconventional, not-quite-romantic relationship with her. Eventually, he comes to suspect that the charismatic leader is using dangerous, extremist methods to further a megalomaniacal cause, leading to a final showdown. If this description sounds familiar without knowing anything more about this new film, you may have seen the movie Fight Club, which turns 20 this fall. At times, The Art of Self-Defense feels like an unofficial remake.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Detective Pikachu surpasses Warcraft as highest-grossing video game film of all time</title><link href="/filmRater/2019/06/29/detective-pikachu-warcraft-highest-grossing-video-game-movie-record.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Detective Pikachu surpasses Warcraft as highest-grossing video game film of all time" /><published>2019-06-29T13:40:00+03:00</published><updated>2019-06-29T13:40:00+03:00</updated><id>/filmRater/2019/06/29/detective-pikachu-warcraft-highest-grossing-video-game-movie-record</id><content type="html" xml:base="/filmRater/2019/06/29/detective-pikachu-warcraft-highest-grossing-video-game-movie-record.html">&lt;p&gt;Detective Pikachu, the live-action mystery movie from director Rob Letterman and Warner Bros. Pictures, has surpassed Duncan Jones’ Warcraft as the highest-grossing video game film of all time with $436 million in worldwide ticket sales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Warcraft, produced by Legendary Pictures (the same company that made Detective Pikachu) and based on the Blizzard Entertainment fantasy franchise, was the previous record-holder since 2016, when it ousted Prince of Persia: The Sands of Time with its $433 million worldwide gross. Warcraft’s success at the time was largely thanks to an enormous marketing campaign in China that translated to then-record overseas ticket sales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, neither of those films came close to Detective Pikachu’s critical reception. Not only is the film — starring Justice Smith as a lapsed pokémon trainer teaming up with a talking pikachu partner voiced by Ryan Reynolds — the highest-earning video game film ever, it’s also the best received.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Detective Pikachu currently holds a 67 percent fresh rating on RottenTomatoes.com, beating out 2018’s Rampage starring Dwayne Johnson, which has a 52 percent rating alongside Alicia Vikander’s Tomb Raider reboot. (Warcraft has an abysmal 26 percent, while Prince of Persia has a 37 percent rating.)
That’s good news for Nintendo, game studio Game Freak, and merchandising and licensing company Creatures, all three of which have equal stakes in the Pokémon franchise. The film itself was based on a 2016 Nintendo 3DS game of the same name developed by Creatures, which occasionally develops video games in addition to overseeing the Pokémon card game, toy lines, and various other media properties. It was published by the three companies’ joint entity, The Pokémon Company, with Nintendo handling distribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The end result of that complex corporate structure is that everyone won out when both the game and the film became commercial successes. So it makes perfect sense that Warner Bros. and Legendary are now looking to make a sequel.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kayla Peers</name></author><summary type="html">Detective Pikachu, the live-action mystery movie from director Rob Letterman and Warner Bros. Pictures, has surpassed Duncan Jones’ Warcraft as the highest-grossing video game film of all time with $436 million in worldwide ticket sales.</summary></entry></feed>